现在是试音时间。
afternoon, Hi, Cindy.
How are you?
I'm fine, thanks.
I'm OK. Where are you going?
To the library.
到此结束。现在播送二零二四年武汉市初中毕业生。学业考试，英语试卷听力部分。该部分分为第一、第二和第三节。注意，做题时先将答案画在试卷。上，该部分录音内容结束后，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到英语答题卡上。第一节：听下面四个问题，每个问题后有三个答语。从题中所给的三个选项中，选出最佳选项。听完每个问题后，你都有五秒钟的时间来作答和阅读下一小题。每个问题仅读一遍。
Text 1. Where are you from?
Text 2. How old is
Text 3. What do you have for lunch?
Text 4. When did the train leave?
第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面八段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中，选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来作答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话仅读一遍。
Text 5. How is the pocket park in the neighborhood?
Very nice! 6.
Darling, which type matches my black suit, the red one or the blue one?
The blue one is better, I think.
Text 7. Wow, you got lots of birthday presents!
Yes, a book, a watch and...
my favorite is the shoes.
Text 8. What's a hot day for a picnic in the woods?
Um, what about going swimming in the sea?
No, it's not safe.
Let's go to the swimming pool in the sports center.
Text 9. I'm going to put the potato pieces in the cooker now.
Is ten minutes enough?
If you want to make them crispy,
five more minutes is OK.
Text 10. You look excited, Mark.
What for? posted my novel online and, to my surprise, many people like it.
Text 11. Who would like to start the discussion, class?
Betty, would you like to go first?
I'm sorry, Mr.
Marley. I haven't prepared for it.
Text 12. Jimmy, are you daydreaming again?
Yes, mum. I dream that I'm taking a walk on the moon.
第二节到此结束。第三节。听下面四段对话或独白，每段对话或独白后有几个小题。从题中所给的三个选项中，选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间。读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍。
14. Text 13.
听下面一段。对话，回答十三至十五三个小题
Hey, Alan. Long time no see.
What do you do now?
Hi, Judy. I work as a waiter.
Oh, really? What restaurant do you work at?
Bob's Cafe. That's cool.
How do you like it?
I'm on my feet all day, so I'm always tired.
What do you do then?
I'm a dancer.
A dancer? How exciting!
Yeah, it's great.
I work with excellent people and learn from them.
That sounds interesting.
But is it difficult?
a little. I'm on my feet all day, too.
But I love it.
Alan. Long time no see.
What do you do now?
Hi, Judy. I work as a waiter.
Oh, really? What restaurant do you work at?
Bob's Cafe. That's cool.
How do you like it?
I'm on my feet all day, so I'm always tired.
What do you do then?
I'm a dancer.
A dancer? How exciting!
Yeah, it's great.
I work with excellent people and learn from them.
That sounds interesting.
But is it difficult?
a little. I'm on my feet all day, too.
But I love it.
听下面一段对话，回答十六至十八三个小题。
Text 14 Hello?
Hi, Kathy. This is Jake.
Are you busy?
No, I'm chatting with Sarah.
Where are you?
Class will start soon.
That's the problem.
I don't think I can make it.
Why not? What's the matter?
My bus is caught in traffic.
Nobody is moving.
Oh, no. What are you going to do?
I don't know.
Could you tell Mr.
White that I'll miss the class?
No problem. I will give him the message.
And could you ask Sarah to take pictures of the white board for me?
Sure. But I can take the pictures for you.
Thanks. But last time you took a picture of the board, all I could see was the wall.
Hello? Hi, Kathy.
This is Jake.
Are you busy?
No, I'm chatting with Sarah.
Where are you?
Class will start soon.
That's the problem.
I don't think I can make it.
Why not? What's the matter?
My bus is caught in traffic.
Nobody is moving.
Oh, no. What are you going to do?
I don't know.
Could you tell Mr.
White that I'll miss the class?
No problem. I will give him the message.
And could you ask Sarah to take pictures of the white board for me?
Sure. But I can take the pictures for you.
Thanks. But last time you took a picture of the board, all I could see was the wall.
听下面一段对话，回答十九至二十二四个小题。
Text 15. What's this, Aunt Lucy?
Can I take it to the yard sale?
That is a record, Max.
I love music just like you do.
How does it work?
I played it on this old record player at home.
Then family or friends would dance together.
Things change. Television used to be just black and white.
You had TV then?
Hey, I'm not that old.
Of course not.
what about the old camera and the handbag?
Can I take them?
Take the camera away, but leave the handbag.
OK. Do you like the old phone?
No. Some new things like smartphones and computers are much easier to use.
But some old things are pretty simple.
Yes. May the old things meet their new owners.
What's this, Aunt Lucy?
Can I take it to the yard sale?
That is a record, Max.
I love music just like you do.
How does it work?
I played it on this old record player at home.
Then family or friends would dance together.
Things change. Television used to be just black and white.
You had TV then?
Hey, I'm not that old.
Of course not.
Oh, what about the old camera and the handbag?
Can I take them?
Take the camera away, but leave the handbag.
OK. Do you like the old phone?
No. Some new things like smartphones and computers are much easier to use.
But some old things are pretty simple.
Yes. May the old things meet their new owners.
听下面一段独白，回答二十三至二十五三个小题。
What's take Lucy?
you do. Text 16 Where are you going for your coming holiday?
Here are some suggestions.
you want to see what life was like 3000 years ago in ancient China,
Anyang is a perfect place to go.
The Yingxu Museum in Anyang is open to the public with nearly 4000 ancient objects.
Every year, thousands of tourists visit Hangzhou.
It's known for its beautiful sights like the West Lake.
And the 19th Asian Games was held there.
The city is a mix of old and new.
When you think of a nature trip, Huangshan Mountain is a good choice.
Standing on the top, you will enjoy a view of mountains, trees and the endless sky.
It's also considered to be a good place to watch the sunrise and sunset.
Text 16 Where are you going for your coming holiday?
Here are some suggestions.
If you want to see what life was like 3000 years ago in ancient China,
Anyang is a perfect place to go.
The Yingxu Museum in Anyang is open to the public with nearly 4000 ancient objects.
Every year, thousands of tourists visit Hangzhou.
It's known for its beautiful sights like the West Lake.
And the 19th Asian Games was held there.
The city is a mix of old and new.
When you think of a nature trip,
Huangshan Mountain is a good choice.
Standing on the top, you will enjoy a view of mountains, trees and the endless sky.
It's also considered to be a good place to watch the sunrise and sunset.
Text Where going for
Here are
第三节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将答案转涂到英语答题卡上。